adsrvr.org 2013-12-31

# Privacy Policy « The Trade Desk

The Trade Desk is committed to protecting consumer privacy and respecting your right to choice as it relates to advertising and the data used to help serve ads relevant to those consumers. The Trade Desk is a technology company which helps advertisers connect with consumers who are interested or could benefit from the advertisers’ products. Protecting consumer privacy is of the utmost priority to The Trade Desk.  See below for our complete Privacy Policy or to opt out of receiving relevant ads served by us.

The following are  **The Trade Desk’s promises to consumers** :

  * We use anonymous user data to serve relevant ads to consumers
  * We use cookies to help match that anonymous data to consumers around the Internet
  * We collect anonymous data about users (which may include information like: sites visited, ads seen, search keywords, ads clicked, shopping information).
  * We do NOT use Personally Identifiable Information to choose what ads to serve to users
  * We do NOT target users who we know are under the age of 13 unless there is explicit parental consent and opt-in
  * We do NOT use any individual level data about health conditions, or specific financial account information to serve behaviorally targeted ads unless a user has explicitly opted in to such ads
  * We do NOT serve ads based on an individual’s sexual orientation or any individual’s visits to sexually explicit websites

If you would prefer not to have The Trade Desk serve you relevant ads, you may opt-out here: [ **Opt Out of Relevant Advertising**](http://www.adsrvr.org/)

The Trade Desk is highly committed to following the OBA Principles and as a member of the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) is in compliance with its Self-Regulatory Code. Click [here](http://www.aboutads.info/principles/) if you would like further information regarding these principles.

Please contact [privacy@thetradedesk.com](mailto:privacy@thetradedesk.com) for any questions about The Trade Desk privacy, security, and data practices. Please see below for our complete Privacy Policy.

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Effective: January 31, 2013**

The Trade Desk (“we”, “us”, or “our”) is an online advertising and technology platform headquartered in the United States. We provide this privacy policy to inform you about how our technology platform (“Technology”) processes information on behalf of online advertisers, website owners, data providers and other businesses that use our services (our “Clients”). This policy also outlines our privacy practices for our corporate website, which is located at [www.thetradedesk.com](http://thetradedesk.com/) (the “Website”).

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please feel free to contact us at [privacy@thetradedesk.com](mailto:privacy@thetradedesk.com).

The Trade Desk runs a buying platform for media and data. The Trade Desk Technology allows our Clients to buy ad space on websites for online advertising and allows for the use of proprietary and third party data in the purchase of that media. When ad space on a website is bought or sold (usually to an advertiser or ad agency by a web publisher) the Technology, as an agent for its Clients, fulfills the transaction by delivering the ad to Internet users who visits that site. Generally, an Internet user’s computer comes into contact with The Trade Desk when a user views an ad, or visits a website, delivered or serviced by or with our Technology. Serving users relevant advertising is sometimes referred to as interest based advertising or online behavioral advertising, “[OBA](http://www.aboutads.info/consumers/#oba)”.

**PRIVACY PRACTICES FOR OUR TECHNOLOGY**

**Information Our Technology Does and Does Not Collect**

Our Technology collects Non-Personally Identifiable Information (“Non-PII”), including, but not limited to, your IP host address, the date and time of the ad request, pages viewed, browser type, the referring URL, Internet Service Provider, and your computer’s operating system. We may also collect Non-PII from Clients or other third parties.

Our Technology may collect Personally Identifiable Information (as defined below) from (i) our Clients or other third parties, and/or (ii) consumers who have consented to such collection practices.  The term “Personally Identifiable Information” or “PII” is information about a specific individual including name, address, telephone number, and email address—when used to identify a particular individual.

The following is PII that we do NOT collect:

  * We do not collect “personal information”, as defined in the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“[COPPA](http://www.coppa.org/comply.htm)”), from users we have actual knowledge are under the age of 13 or from sites directed to children under the age of 13 for OBA, nor do we engage in OBA directed to children we have actual knowledge are under the age of 13 except as compliant with the COPPA.
  * The Trade Desk also does not collect or use financial account numbers, Social Security numbers, pharmaceutical prescriptions, or medical records about a specific individual for Online Behavioral Advertising.

**How We Use Information Our Technology Collects**

The Trade Desk uses Non-PII to target and serve relevant advertising to consumers and to perform attribution analysis or other analytics regarding advertising audiences. Our Technology does NOT use any PII to serve advertisements to consumers, and we do not sell any of your PII.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

In order to help make the online advertisements more relevant to users, our Technology uses the standard “cookies” feature of major browser applications that allows us to store a small piece of data on users’ computers about users’ visits to certain websites. We also use cookies to understand users’ browsing and buying activities so that we can measure the success of online advertising campaigns we run.

Cookies are small text files that web servers typically send to users’ computer when they visit a website. Cookies are stored as text files on users’ hard drive, and can be accessed by web servers when the user visits a website or views an advertisement. Cookies are used by companies to collect and send information about a user’s website visit – for example, number of visits, average time spent, pages viewed, navigation history through the website, and other statistics. This information helps companies improve a user’s online experience in many ways: for example, by allowing companies to monitor website performance, making the website easier to use, measuring the effectiveness of their promotional placements, and tailoring their website (including the ads and offers they receive) to better match a user’s interests and preferences. _  The cookies placed by our Technology cannot be used to access any other data on a user’s hard drive, or to personally identify them._ Users who prefer not to accept cookies can set their Internet browser to notify them when they receive a cookie or to prevent cookies from being placed on their hard drive.

The Trade Desk cookie is set to expire after one year, this expiration is a sliding window, meaning it resets itself after any interaction occurs.

The Trade Desk also uses web beacons (also known as 1×1 gifs), along with cookies, to determine if a user has visited a particular website. These beacons aid in providing more relevant advertising to the user, as well measuring the success of an advertising campaign, but provide no personally identifiable information.

**Opt-Out From Our Cookies**

If you’d like to opt-out from having The Trade Desk collect your Non-PII in connection with our Technology, please click [here](http://www.adsrvr.org/). When you opt out, we will place an opt-out cookie on your computer. The opt-out cookie tells us not to collect your Non-PII to tailor our online advertising campaigns. Please note that if you delete, block or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice. Please also note that if you choose to disable this function, your online experience may be diminished and some features may not work as they were intended.

The online advertising industry also provides websites from which you may opt-out of receiving targeted ads from our data and advertising partners.  You can access these, and also learn more about targeted advertising and consumer choice and privacy, at [http://www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) and at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

**Information Sharing**

The Trade Desk may share aggregated, non-personal information with Clients in connection with reporting and accounting needs as well as with other unaffiliated third parties for various purposes such as statistical or educational analysis. In some instances we may share Client contact information in an offline process that includes PII—like name, email address and company—with select service providers and partners of The Trade Desk who provide relevant services for our Clients. None of this PII is tied to you the user or any cookied user in our Technology.

We may disclose your information to third parties when we reasonably believe we are obligated to do so by law, and in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding suspected or actual prohibited activities, including but not limited to, fraud and situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person.

Also, in the event The Trade Desk is merged into another company, or another company acquires all or substantially all of The Trade Desk’s assets, including, without limitation, in the event of bankruptcy, all data compiled or owned by The Trade Desk may be among the items transferred in that transaction. In such event, all the data will continue to be governed by this policy.

**Data Storage and Security**

We retain the non-Personally Identifiable Information collected via our Technology for up to 180 days.  After 180 days the data is stored in aggregate for up to three years.  In instances where local laws are more stringent, we adhere to the local laws where we are doing business.

The security of your information is important to us.  The Trade Desk has implemented reasonable security measures to prevent the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information that our Technology collects, but we make no assurances about our ability to prevent such loss, misuse, to you or to any third party arising out of any such loss, misuse, or alteration.

**Changes To Our Policy**

We may revise this policy at any time. Any changes and/or updates to the policy will be updated directly on this page. We encourage you to visit this page periodically to review our current privacy policy so that you will always know what information we gather and how we may use that information. In the event we make any material changes to this policy we will advise our Clients of such changes in advance.

**Contacting Us**

****Should you have any questions in regards to this policy or The Trade Desk’s privacy practices, please contact our representatives at the following email and they will be more than happy to clarify and assist you in any way possible:  [privacy@thetradedesk.com](mailto:privacy@thetradedesk.com), or by mail at:

Privacy

The Trade Desk, Inc.  
505 Poli Street, 5th Floor  
Ventura, CA 93001

**PRIVACY PRACTICES FOR OUR WEBSITE**

**Information We Collect On Our Website**

****On the Careers or Contact Us sections of the Website, we may collect PII. The information that The Trade Desk records is for reply only and is later on erased with no further use. The Trade Desk does not match any of this data with the cookies-based data our Technology collects.

We may also collect Non-PII from visitors to this Website for a variety of reasons including to streamline website usability.

**How We Use Information We Collect On Our Website**

On this Website, PII is only collected in the Careers section if you were to submit a resume to us for recruiting purposes or on the Contact Us, Request a Demo, Get More Info, or Newsletter Signup sections.

**Third Party Websites**

****The Trade Desk Website may contain links to and advertisements for websites operated by third parties whose privacy practices may differ from ours. While we endeavor to associate only with reputable entities, The Trade Desk is not responsible for the privacy practices of these other websites. We encourage you to check the privacy policies of all websites that you visit.

**Updating / Deleting your PII**

If you’d like us to update, correct, delete, or deactivate any PII that you have provided to us on this Website, please resubmit your contact information on the Contact Us page or send your request to us at [privacy@thetradedesk.com](mailto:privacy@thetradedesk.com) and we will process your request within a reasonable period of time after receipt.
